Mss.B.Sca42
American Philosophical Society
- Series IV. Military, legal,and financial documents, 1459-1847 October 22; 142.0 folders
  - Scaliger, Julius Caesar- sachent tous, 1536 September 14; 1.0 item (Box Oversize 2, Folder 5)
    This is a square of parchment that is ripped at the bottom. It begins with the line "sachent tous presens..." found on other documents. There is a signature at the bottom.
  - Document, 1537 August 19; 1.0 item (Box Oversize 4, Folder 6)
    This document is written on a large rectangle of parchment with a single signature written in a different color ink than the rest of the document.
  - Exchange, 1539 October 19; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 1)
    The full title reads, "exchange de noble et bienveillant homme...de Lescale docteur de medicine et Johan Mesani"
    Unidentified
  - Document from the king, 1543 October; 1.0 item (Box Seal)
  - Scaliger, Julius Caesar- document, 1545 October 2; 1.0 item (Box Oversize 4, Folder 7)
    This document is written on a large rectangle of parchement. It begins with the phrase "sachent tous..." seen on several of the documents.
  - Exchange, 1546 July 13; 1.0 item (Box Oversize 2, Folder 6)
  - Sachent tous, 1546 October 20; 1.0 item (Box Oversize 2, Folder 7)
    This is a rectangle of parchment that is ripped along the bottom. The text begins with the words, "sachent tous presene."
  - Lettres..de Henry d'Albret, roy de Navarre, 1548 January; 1.0 item (Box Oversize 4, Folder 8)
    Henry IV, King of France, 1553-1610; Scaliger, Julius Caesar, 1484-1558
  - Scaliger, Julius Caesar- letter permitting him to be a doctor, 1548 January 16; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Note written on the original folder reads "Copy of letter...making J.C. Scaliger doctor in ordinance of the King of Navarre."
    Scaliger, Julius Caesar, 1484-1558 -- Correspondence
  - Acte justification, 1548 November 22; 1.0 item (Box Oversize 2, Folder 8)
    A note on the back of the document reads that it was an act of justification by Jules Cezar to the Council of Agen.
  - Sachent tous, 155-; 1.0 item (Box Oversize 2, Folder 9)
    This is a rectangle of parchment with a signature on the bottom. The text begins with the words, "sachent tous presene."
  - Document from the royal court, 1550 July; 1.0 item (Box Oversize 4, Folder 9)
  - Scaliger, Julius Caesar- sachent tous, 1550 August 22; 1.0 item (Box Oversize 2, Folder 10)
    This document is a large square of parchment that begins with the words, "sachent tous..." and there is a signature at the bottom.
  - Scaliger, Julius Caesar- sachent tous, 1550 November 10; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 3)
    This document is is written on parchment with a crest stamped on it and signitures at the bottom. The text begins with the words "sachent tous" that is found as the introductory words on several other documents.
  - Recognoissance de guillem, 1551; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Scaliger, Julius Caesar- sachent tous, 1553 October; 1.0 item (Box Oversize 2, Folder 11)
  - Sachent tous, 1555; 1.0 item (Box Oversize 2, Folder 12)
  - Scaliger, Julius Caesar- sachent tous, 1556; 1.0 item (Box Oversize 2, Folder 13)
  - Scaliger, Julius Caesar- will, about 1558; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Scaliger, Julius Caeser- will, 1558 September 15; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Scaliger, Julius Caesar- will, 1558 September 15; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Document, 1559; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 8)
    This document is written on a small square sheet of paper. There is one paragraph of text on one side and a sentance on the other. The name Catherine as well as de Lascalle is mentioned.
  - Lescale de Vérone, Anne de and Charrier, Jean de- announcement of marriage, 1562 January 4; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Charrier, Jean de; Lescale de Vérone, Anne de, after 1528-1619
  - Lescale, Joseph de- document, 1564 May 30; 1.0 item (Box Oversize 2, Folder 14)
    This document is a rectangle of parchment with a block of text, signature at the bottom, and notes on the left-hand margin. Judging based on the year that the document was written the Joseph that it refers to is most likely Joseph Juste Scaliger.
    Scaliger, Joseph Juste, 1540-1609
  - Requeste, 1566; 1.0 item (Box Oversize 2, Folder 15)
    A note written on the back of the document reads, "requeste civille pour Joseph de Lescalle escuyer Sr. de Colombec Roy, Charles." Judging based on the year that the document was written the Joseph that it refers to is most likely Joseph Juste Scaliger.
  - Document, 1569 October; 1.0 item (Box Oversize 2, Folder 16)
    This document is a rectangular shaped piece of paper with a crest stamped on it and a signature at the bottom. The text mentions the king and could be an ordinance.
  - Sauve garde, 1571 December 6; 2.0 items (Box Oversize 2, Folder 17)
    The full title is, "Sauve garde des maison de Lescale par le prince de Navarre, signé Henry." A note dated April 20, 1946 in the original folder with the document reads, "Dr. Ghenard says autographs of Henry the IV of this date are rare." This note is also in this folder.
    Henry IV, King of France, 1553-1610; Scaliger
  - Contract, 1575 May 19; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Contract de transaction, 1583 June 20; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Goulard, Henry Renée de and Narbonne, Agelillan de- marriage contract, 1596 June 15; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 13)
    There are two pages of inclosed notes and family trees probably written at a much later date.
    Goulard, Henry Renée de; Narbonne, Agelillan de
  - Obligation, 1598 September 14; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph Juste de
  - Contract, 1600 April 14; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph Juste de; Lescale de Vérone, Anne de, after 1528-1619
  - Lescale de Vérone, Anne de and Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph de- sachent tous, 1600 May 15; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 16)
    This document is a small booklet of papers. The text begins with the words "sachent tous qui ces presentes..." that is found as the introductory words on several other documents. There are poritions of the document underlined and notes written in the margins.
    Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph de, -1689; Lescale de Vérone, Anne de, after 1528-1619
  - Document, 1607 September; 1.0 item (Box Oversize 3, Folder 1)
    This item is a booklet of parchment that mentions the Lescalles.
    This document can be found in Oversize Box 3.
  - Sachent tous, 1607 December; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 17)
    This document was found in the same folder as "Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph de- document" dated 1529 April 15, "Arrest" dated 1672 May 21, and "Scaliger, Julius Caesar- exchange" dated 1672 August 29. It is written on parchment and the text begins with the words "sachent tous" that is found as the introductory words on several other documents.
  - Document from the king, 1578 March; 1.0 item (Box Seal)
  - Scaliger, Joseph Juste- section of will, 1609 February 20; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Scalla, Joseph della- will, 1609 November; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Scaliger, Joseph Justus- will, 1609 November 18; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph Juste de and La Brunetiere, Catherine de- marriage contract, 1614 April 3; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 21)
    Catherine de, La Brunetiere; Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph Juste de
  - Extrait des registres, 1614 April 13; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 22)
    The full title reads, "Extrait des registres des immuations du greffe de la cour de la sénéchaussée es siege presedial d'agennois de l'annee 1614"
  - Lescale de Vérone, Anne de- will, 1619 April 21; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 23)
    On the back of this document a note suggests that this is the document in which Anne de Lescale de Verone bestows the name and arms of the Lescale family on her son, Joseph de Charrier de Lescale de Verone
    Lescale de Vérone, Anne de, after 1528-1619
  - Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph de- document, 1620 September 27; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 24)
    This is about a six inch by eight inch folded piece of paper. A note on the back mentions that it was made by Joseph de Charryer escuyer and the last sentance reads, "...eu deporter le nom et avenir Mammejan de Lescalle."
    Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph de, -1689; Monmejan
  - Marriage Contract, 1622 January; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Document, circa 1625 September 4; 1.0 item (Box Oversize 3, Folder 2)
    This document is actually two packets of paper tied together. A note at the end of the first packet reads, "par l'arrest de la cour de parlement et chambre de guiennel." It names several members of the Scaliger family including Joseph de L'escalle Charrier, Anne de Lescalle, and Julles Caesar de Lescalle as well as legal documents including wills.
    The second packet of papers is dated 1625 September 4 and is written in a similar handwriting to the first packet. It too names members of the Scaliger family and legal documents. Both packets contain notes in the margins and underlined portions at times in a different ink color than the text.
  - Liquidation tant des biens, 1625 September 4; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 26)
    The title is difficult to read but seems to be something such as, "Liquidation tant des biens...par Julles Casar de Lescale et des droits apartenant a la substitution que ligitisme et quarto tribulanique"
  - Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph Juste and Lescale de Vérone, Anne- document, 1626 August 22; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 27)
    This is a packet of parchment. A note on the back reads, "arrest contactoire de la chambre de l'ecrit de guienne"
  - Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph Juste- document, 1627 January 16; 1.0 item (Box Oversize 3, Folder 3)
    This document is a packet of parchment about seven inches by eleven inches with two additional sheets (one of paper and one of parchment) attached to the front of it
  - Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph Juste- inheritance document, 1627 May 14; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 28)
    This is a small booklet of paper. It seems that the front sheet was attached afterwards. The text begins, "la partie de Joseph de Lescalle Charrier escuier nomme heretier de...Anne de Lescalle damoiselle sa mere..."
  - Factum pour Mes. Jean Mommejan, after 1629; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Contract, 1632 November 17; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Document, 1635 March 24; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 31)
    This document is comprised of one sheet of paper folded in half with several paragraphs of writing on both sides and signatures at the bottom.
  - Lescale, Joseph de- document, 1644 November 20; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 32)
    This is a small booklet of several pages. The text contains signatures and underlined portions. The name on the document is simply Joseph de Lescale, which is ambigious given that there is Joseph Juste de Charrier de Lescale de Vérone as well as his son with a very similar name, Joseph de Charrier de Lescale de Vérone.
    Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph de, -1689; Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph Juste de
  - Lescale, Joseph de and Vaux, Nicole de- transaction, 1645 July 13; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 33)
    It is difficult to know which Joseph this transaction refers to, Joseph Juste de Charrier de Lescale de Vérone or his son Joseph de Charrier de Lescale de Vérone.
  - Troops sent to the King- series of dated notes, 1649 February 10-176- February 4; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Commission du roy, 1649 February 11; 1.0 item (Box Seal)
    The full title is difficult to read but could say, "Commission du roy pour les de Lescalle auquel...donne le compagne d'infantry dans le regimen de Candalle"
  - Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph de- certificate for the military services in Candalle, 1650s; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Changement de nom, 1650 June 15; 1.0 item (Box 5, Folder 36)
    There are actually two documents connected by a wax seal. They are written in two different handwritings and while the first has the date 15 June 1650 it is the second document that is entitled "Changement de nom"
  - Orders from the King, 1650 August 14; 1.0 item; Louis XIV, King of France, 1638-1715 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Orders from the King, 1650 October 6; 1.0 item; Louis XIV, King of France, 1638-1715 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Pour nos sepulchres, 1652 November 20; 2.0 items (Box 6, Folder 1)
    These two documents were grouped together in their original folder so they have been kept together. There is one item with a note on the back that reads, "pour nos sepulchres d'agen et de montbran." The other document includes notes from the legal documents of Julius Caesar Scaliger and Joseph de Lescale among others.
    The full title reads, "Pour nos sepulchres d'agen et de montbran and notes from legal documents from members of the Scaliger family"
  - Document, 1652 April; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 2)
    The signature on the bottom of the document mentions Candalle so there may be a connection to Joseph de Charrier de Lescale de Vérone who served as a captain in a regiment in Candalle.
  - Document about the military, 1653 August; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph de- agreement, 1656 November 22; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph de and Salleles, Izabeau de- articles and conditions of marriage, 1657; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph de, -1689; Sallales, Izabeau de
  - Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph de and Saleles, Izerbeau de- marriage contract, 1657 January 8; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph de and Sallellea, Izabeau de- copy of marriage contract, 1657 January 8; 1.0 item (Box Oversize 3, Folder 4)
  - Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph de- document, 1660; 1.0 item (Box Seal)
    The handwriting used on this document is difficult to read making it hard to discern what kind of document it is but it is signed by King Louis XIV and, given the time period, is probably concerned with the nobility of Joseph de Charrier de Lescale de Vérone.
    Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph de, -1689; Louis XIV, King of France, 1638-1715
  - Changement de nom, 1660 May 21; 1.0 item (Box Seal)
  - Document, 1660 August 18; 1.0 item (Box Oversize 3, Folder 5)
    This is a single sheet of paper about eleven inches by eight inches with a paragraph of text on it. At the bottom there are three signatures.
  - Changement de nom, 1660 December 20; 1.0 item (Box Oversize 3, Folder 6)
  - Production des titres, 1666 September 10; 1.0 item (Box Oversize 3, Folder 7)
    The full title reads, "Production des titres du Sieur de Lescale pour veriffier sa noblesse par devant les commissaire subdelegue au pied de laquelle ils son..."
  - Marriage Contract, 1670 November 23; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Arrest, 1672 May 21; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 8)
    This item was found in the same folder as "Scaliger, Julius Caesar- exchange" dated 1529 April 15, "Sachent tous" dated 1607 December, and "Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph de- document" dated 1672 August 29.
    The first word of a note on the back of this document is "arrest." It mentions Joseph de Lescalle, which, given the date, probably refers to Joseph de Charrier de Lescale de Vérone.
  - Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph de- document, 1672 August 29; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 9)
    This document is a single piece of almost translucent parchment. It consists of one paragaph followed by signitures at the bottom of the page. The text mentions noble Joseph de Lescalle de Veronne as well as the king.
    This document was found in the same original folder as "Scaliger, Julius Caesar- exchange"dated 1529 April 15, "Arrest" dated 1672 May 21, and "Sachent tous" dated 1607 December.
    Note: By accident there are two Box 6 Folder 9. Make sure you have the right one.
  - Orders from Monseigneur le Marschal d'Albret, 1674 April 12; 1.0 item (Box Oversize 3, Folder 8)
  - Orders from the King, 1674 July 4; 1.0 item; Louis XIV, King of France, 1638-1715 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    The title on this document reads, "le Mareschal d'Albret chevalier des ordres du roy, gouverneur et lieutenant general pour sa maieste en Guyenne"
  - Contract de delayssent, 1675 March; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph de- document, 1676; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 11)
    This is a small booklet of documents with a stamp on the front that reads, "Generalite de Bordeaux." After the text there are signatures.
  - Reflexions, after 1666 and circa 1688; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 12)
    The full title reads, "Reflexions a faire sur les requests des consuls de la ville d'agen par lesquelles ils ont impugné les titres memoires et documents que noble Joseph de Lescale de Verone escuiera produit devant la cour des aydes de guiene affin de prouver sa noblesse"
    The full title reads, "Reflexions a faire sur les requests des consuls de la ville d'agen"
  - Reponces aux contredits des consuls d'agen, after 1671, circa 1688; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Document from the King on Scaliger family heritage, 1684 February 14; 1.0 item; Louis XIV, King of France, 1638-1715 (Box Oversize 3, Folder 9)
  - Exploit de signiffication, 1684 February 14; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 14)
    Paired in the same folder as "Lescale de Vérone, Julius Caesar de- document" from 16 September 1699
    The full title reads, "Exploit de signiffication fait a les consuls dágen le 14 fevrier 1684." This document was paired in the same original folder as "Lescalle de Verone, Julles Cezar de- document" dated 1699 September 16. This doument is one sheet of paper folded in half with a paragraph written on the front and signatures at the bottom. The text of this document begins with the date but then notes that it was created at the request of noble Joseph de Lescal de Vérone, Captain of the infantry at Candale.
  - Document, 1687 April; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 15)
    This is a small rectangle of parchment written in Latin with signatures at the bottom.
  - Document, circa 1688; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 16)
    This document consists of a single sheet of paper with what appears to be notes written on both sides. Some of the notes include military terms such as "la compagnie" and several different dates within the year 1688 are mentioned.
  - Dire contenant responces, 1688 April 2; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 17)
    The full title reads, "Dire contenant responces aux defances des consulz de la ville d'agen fondées sur trois chefs"
  - Inventaire des tiltres, 1688 March 31; 1.0 item; Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph de, -1689 (Box Oversize 3, Folder 10)
    The full title reads, "Inventaire des tiltres et memoires que noble Joseph de Lescale de Verone eseuyer produit devant nos seigneurs de la cour des aydes de guyenne"
  - Provés verbal, 1688 November 13; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 18)
    The full title reads, "Provés verbal fait en bonne et d'hue forme des armoiries et timbre de Jule Caesar Scaliger et signiffié aux consuls d'agen"
  - Lescale de Vérone II, Julius Ceasar de and Monmejan, Marie de- marriage contract, 1689 January 1; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 19)
    Lescale de Vérone, Julius Caesar de, -1726; Monmejan, Marie de; Monmejan
  - Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph de- will, 1689 May 2; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Lescale de Vérone, Joseph de- document about his title, 1690 August 2; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Extrait de Register, 1690 August 20; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 22)
    The full title is difficult to read but appears to be, "Extrait de Register de la cour...entre Jozeph de Lescale de Veroune"
  - Conclusions d'entre Joseph Lescalle de Veronne a les consuls d'agen, 1690 August 21; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Scaliger, Julius Caesar- document, 1690 December; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 24)
    This is a small booklet of paper with underlined portions and a few notes in the margin. The name Juliud Cesarus Escaligeri is underlined don the first page.
  - Monmejan, Francois de and Ietoueoz, Anthoniette - marriage contract, 1693 June 28; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 25)
    Ietoueoz, Anthoniette; Monmejan, Francois de; Monmejan
  - Order issued by Mrs les Commissaires Généraux de Conseil, 1698 February 21; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Lescale de Vérone, Julius Caesar de and Monmejan, Marie de 1689- marriage contract, 1699 January 1; 1.0 item (Box Oversize 3, Folder 11)
    Lescale de Vérone, Julius Caesar de, -1726; Monmejan, Marie de
  - Mademoiselle de Monmejan- transaction, 1699 January 16; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Monmejan, Francois de and Ietoueoz, Anthoniette- document, 1699 September 7; 1.0 item (Box Oversize 3, Folder 12)
    The handwriting used on this document is difficult to read making it hard to discern what kind of document it is.
    Ietoueoz, Anthoniette; Lescale de Vérone, Julius Caesar de, -1726; Monmejan, Francois de
  - Lescalle de Verone, Julles Cezar de- document, 1699 September 16; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 28)
    This document was paired in the same original folder as "Exploit de signiffication fait a les consuls dágen le 14 fevrier 1684" from 1684 February 14. On the front is a stamp with the word "intandant" on it and the first sentance clarifies, "intandant de justice police et finances"
    Charrier de Lescale de Vérone, Joseph de, -1689; Lescale de Vérone, Julius Caesar de, -1726
  - Collection of papers, circa 1700; 7.0 items (Box 6, Folder 29)
    There are seven individual pieces of paper. One is labeled "Election d'Agen" and several of the others have "recu" written at the top. The handwriting on each of the sheets varies and some are dated from around 1700 but not all.
  - Election d'Agen capitation, 1701 January; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Recu de Noble Julles Cezar de Lescalle, 1701 November 16; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Fouvon, Anthionette- will, 1705 December 10; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 32)
    Anthionette Fouvon was the wife of Francois de Monmejan.
    Ietoueoz, Anthoniette
  - Collection of legal documents, 1706 February 4-1755 February 26; 7.0 items (Box 6, Folder 33)
    This folder includes seven individual documents dated from a range of different years.
    Lescale de Vérone, Joseph Juste Caesar de, -1755 February 26; Montault de Saint Civier, Marie Josephe
  - Transaction, 1721 July 6; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Nomination, 1722 December 15; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 35)
    The full title reads, "Nomination faire par le Monseiur de Lescale père en faveur du Monseiur de Verone son fils ayne"
    Lescale de Vérone, Joseph Juste Caesar de, -1755 February 26; Lescale de Vérone, Julius Caesar de, -1726
  - Transaction passée entre les Monsieurs de Verone, frères, 1723 February 13; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 36)
    Lescale de Vérone, Joseph Juste Caesar de, -1755 February 26; Scaliger
  - Lescale de Vérone II, Julius Caesar de- will, 1726 April 20; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Lescale de Vérone, Joseph Juste Caesar and Marchaud, Francois Lacaze- transaction, 1734 August 28; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 38)
    Lescale de Vérone, Joseph Juste Caesar de, -1755 February 26
  - Lescale de Vérone, Marie de- will, 1742 June 2; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 39)
    Lescale de Vérone, Marie de, -1742
  - Lescale de Vérone, Anne de- will, 1749 June 28; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 40)
    Lescale de Vérone, Marie Magdeline de, -1749 July 20
  - Lescale de Vérone, Mary Magdeline- will, 1749 July 20; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 41)
    A note on the back of the document reads, "testament de Demoiselle Marie Magdeline Lescalle de Veronne par lequel elle institue son heritier Nobel Joseph Juste Caesar de Lescalle de Veronne Escuyer seigneur de viver"
  - Obligation, 1752 October 20; 1.0 item (Box 6, Folder 42)